早上好，长官，医生
Good morning, sir. Doctor.
- 有问题吗？ - 是的
- Something wrong? - Yes.
虽然不明白问题在哪，我总觉得那人不对劲
There's something odd about that man and I can't quite pinpoint it.
可能只是你草率的个人偏见
Perhaps you're making a rather hasty judgement.
诺曼先生上舰才72小时
Mr. Norman has only been aboard 72 hours.
好吧，我的直觉告诉我他不正常
Well, I know when something doesn't strike me right, and he doesn't.
医生，准确的说，这是下结论而不是推理
Specifics, doctor. Labels do not make arguments.
好吧
All right.
一个从来不笑
There's something wrong about a man who never smiles,
对话内容仅限于日常工作
whose conversation never varies from the routine of the job,
也不肯谈起自己背景的人，就是有问题的
and who won't talk about his background.
我明白了
I see.
史波克
Spock.
我的意思是，对一个非瓦肯人来说，他很奇怪
I mean that it's odd for a non-Vulcan.
耳朵不同，不能相提并论
The ears make all the difference.
我认为你的论据存在很大的逻辑缺陷
I find your argument strewn with gaping defects in logic.
也许吧，但是你不能单凭逻辑去评价一个人
Maybe, but you can't evaluate a man by logic alone.
再说，他已经无故缺席了
Besides, he has avoided two appointments
两次身体检查
that I've made for his physical exam, without reason.
这一点都不奇怪，医生
That's not at all surprising, doctor.
他可能是被你那些稀奇古怪的仪器吓坏了
He's probably terrified of your beads and rattles.
未授权人员不得入内
非指挥人员不得…
Command personnel only...
超负荷！危险！
苏鲁先生，怎么了？
Yes, Mr. Sulu.
有人私自改变了计划航向，舰长
There's an unplanned course change being fed into the instruments, sir.
修正航向
Correct it.
无法修正，舰长
I can't, sir.
辅助控制室，我是舰长
Auxiliary Control, this is the captain.
辅助控制室，你们那边怎么回事？
Auxiliary Control, what's going on down there?
舰长，辅助控制室被控制了
Sir, Auxiliary Control is on total override.
寇克呼叫安保部
Kirk to Security.
收到，我是罗维上尉
Security. Lieutenant Rowe here, sir.
入侵警报，8号甲班，辅助控制室
Intruder alert. Deck 8. Auxiliary Control.
明白
Acknowledged.
乌乎拉上尉，请史波克到舰桥报道
Lieutenant Uhura, have Mr. Spock report to the Bridge.
是，舰长
Aye, sir.
新航线去哪，苏鲁？
What's the imposed course, Mr. Sulu?
转向307度，标记8
Turning on 307 degrees, mark 8.
现在已执行，舰长
Being executed now, sir.
照顾好他
Take care of him.
- 安保部呼叫寇克舰长 - 我是寇克
- Security to Captain Kirk. - Kirk here.
我是罗维上尉，舰长，我在辅助控制室里
Lieutenant Rowe, sir. I'm in Auxiliary Control.
乔丹少尉被击昏了
Ensign Jordan's been knocked out.
航向主控卡住了
The directional master controls have been jammed.
完全失灵了
They're totally unworkable.
- 有没有入侵者的迹象？ - 没有，舰长，他消失了
- Any sign of the intruder? - No, sir. He's gone.
我会命令所有甲板进入警戒状态
I've put out a full security alert on all decks.
找到他，完毕
Find him. Kirk out.
史波克，我们似乎正在进入一条计划外的航线
Mr. Spock, we seem to be taking an unscheduled ride.
有意思
Interesting.
苏鲁
Mr. Sulu.
切换到应急手动监控室，终止越权行为
Cut into Emergency Manual Monitor. I want the override broken.
舰长，仪器没有反应
Sir, the instruments won't respond.
应急手动监控室，报告
Emergency Manual Monitor, report.
我是寇克舰长，请回答
This is Captain Kirk. Acknowledge.
应急手动控制室，我是舰长，请回答
Emergency Manual Monitor. This is the captain, report.
嘿，你不能…
Here, you're not allowed...
请回答，我是舰长，史考特，请回答
Acknowledge. This is the captain. Scotty, acknowledge.
史考特，你那边怎么了？寇克呼叫轮机室
Scotty, what's going on down there? Kirk to Engineering.
我是舰长，史考特，请回答
This is the captain. Scotty, report!
史考特，入侵者在你那边
Scotty, the intruder is in your area.
到底发生什么了，史考特！
What's going on down there? Scotty!
- 舰长，他在这里 - 史考特
- Captain. He's here. - Scotty.
史考特
Scotty.
史考特？
Scotty?
安保部
Security.
入侵者在轮机室，派人过去
The intruder's in Engineering. Have all units converge on that point.
舰长，我们在加速，曲速5、曲速6…已经达到曲速7
Sir, we're picking up speed. Warp 5, 6. Warp 7, sir.
切断动力
Cut power.
无法切断，舰长，所有控制系统都卡住了
I can't, sir. All the controls are jammed.
史波克，你接手指挥
Spock, take over.
不必了，舰长
It will not be necessary, captain.
通知安保部我们找到入侵者了
Tell Security we found the intruder.
请向我们解释一下，这是怎么回事？
You mind telling me what this is all about, mister?
我已经全面控制了你的星舰
I am in total control of your ship.
我已经将反物质隔舱连接到主导航数据库了
I have connected the matter-antimatter pods to the main navigational bank.
我安装了一个引爆器
A trigger relay is now in operation.
任何试图改变航向的行为
Any attempts to alter course
都会导致这艘星舰灰飞烟灭
will result in the immediate destruction of this vessel.
史波克？
Spock?
没错，舰长，他已经掌握了所有权限
Confirmed, captain. He's taken out all the override controls.
如果我们没有找出引爆器就贸然行动的话…
If we tamper without knowing where the trigger relay is...
…就会葬送自己
...we could extinguish ourselves.
你是谁？
Who are you?
我向你保证，我们对人类或类人生物…
I assure you, we are no threat to humanity...
…没有任何威胁
...or humanoid life.
我们无意伤害你们
We mean you no harm.
只是需要你们的星舰
But we require your ship.
你需要…？你说的“我们”究竟是谁？
You require..? Who and what are "we"?
宇宙，最后的边疆
Space, the final frontier.
这是星舰进取号的航程
These are the voyages of the starship Enterprise.
它的五年任务，是去探索未知的新世界
Its five-year mission: To explore strange new worlds,
找寻新的生命与新的文明
to seek out new life and new civilisations,
勇敢的航向前人未至之境
to boldly go where no man has gone before.
【星际迷航：原初】
-=THE LAST FANTASY=-
荣誉出品
本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业途径
-=TLF字幕组=-
翻译：诺阿诺阿
校对：喜马拉雅
第二季第八集
「马德一世」
- 机器人 - 而且还相当精密复杂
- An android. - And most sophisticated.
我控制着引爆器，先生
I control the trigger relay, sir.
不要妄图用蛮力战胜我
I cannot be overcome by physical means.
如果你试图使用相位枪
And if you attempt to use your phasers,
引爆器便会被激活
the trigger relay will be activated.
我们将按照目前的路线航行约
We shall continue on our present course for approximately
四个地球日，到时将抵达
four solar days, at which time we shall arrive
我们的目的地
at our destination.
谁派你来的？
Who sent you?
我的程序设定不允许我回答这类问题
I am not programmed to respond in that area.
看来他是自动关机了，舰长
He simply appears to have turned himself off, captain.
鉴于我们无法在保全星舰的前提下
And since we cannot repair the damage he has done
恢复星舰的功能
without destroying the ship...
那我们当做是在旅行吧
It seems we're going to take a little trip.
舰长日志，星历4513.3
Captain's log, stardate 4513.3.
自从被机器人接管之后
After having been taken over by an android,
企业号已经以曲速7航行了4天
the Enterprise has been under way at warp 7 for four days.
现在，我们正进入一颗地图上
Now, we are entering orbit
从未标示出的行星的轨道
around a planet which has never been charted.
寇克舰长
Captain Kirk.
请将以下人员传送至我们星球：
The following individuals will be transported down to our planet:
您自己，科学官
Yourself, science officer,
医疗官
medical officer,
通讯官
communications officer,
以及领航员
and navigator.
任何形式的会面都必须在企业号上进行
Any meetings or discussions can be held aboard the Enterprise.
如果不跟我走，引擎就会被摧毁
If you do not come with me, your engines will be destroyed
你们将永远在停留在这里
and you will remain in orbit here forever.
让我感谢您真诚的邀请
I must say, that's a gracious invitation.
有一个词
There is a word.
在我们的语言中没有与之对应的含义
Among us, there is no corresponding meaning.
但是对于你们来说似乎很有意义
But it seems to mean something to you humans.
哪个词呢？
And what is that word?
请
Please.
按照你们的分类标准，我们星球表面属于K型
Our planet's surface is what you classify as K-type.
借助大气穹顶和生命维持系统
Adaptable for humans by use of pressure domes
人类也可在此生存
and life-support systems.
- 我把他们带来了 - 他在等着
- I have brought them. - He is waiting.
请随我来
If you will follow us, please.
这不可能！
I don't believe it.
欢迎登陆，寇克
Welcome aboard, Kirk.
好久不见了啊
Been a long time, eh?
哈里·马德！
Harry Mudd!
小伙子，准确来说
Well, to be absolutely accurate, laddie buck,
你应该称我为：马德一世
you should refer to me as Mudd the First,
这颗自治行星的统治者
ruler of this entire sovereign planet.
统治者？
Ruler?
请立即交还我方星舰的控制权
I want control of my ship returned immediately.
我们无意逗留
We have no intention of staying.
这个嘛，恐怕有一点问题
Well, I'm afraid there's a bit of a problem there.
- 寇克呼叫进取号，寇克呼叫进取号 - 爱丽丝
- Kirk to Enterprise. Kirk to Enterprise. - Alice.
好了，小詹姆，没有我允许，不要随便说话
Now, now, Jamie boy, let's have no unauthorised communications.
你认识他吗，舰长？
You know this man, captain?
岂止认识，哈考特·芬东·马德
Do I know him? Harcourt Fenton Mudd.
- 窃贼 - 行了行了
- Thief. - Come now.
- 游手好闲 - 企业家
- Swindler and con man. - Entrepreneur.
- 无恶不作 - 在你心目中我就是这种人？
- Liar and rogue. - Did I leave you with that impression?
应该待在我亲手关你进去的监狱
Belongs in jail, which is where I left you.
从此成为传说，没错
And thereby hangs a tale, yes.
可是看看你周围啊，寇克
But look around you, Kirk.
这地方不错吧？
Quite a place here, isn't it?
- 希望你们能喜欢 - 马德
- I hope you're all going to enjoy it. - Mudd.
让你那个叫诺曼的机器人
I want that trained machine of yours, Norman,
解除引爆器
to deactivate the trigger mechanism
还我的星舰自由
and free my ship.
- 等时机成熟时我自然会这么做 - 我告诉你
- I shall do that when I'm ready. - I'm telling you now.
我告诉你！这里我说了算，老伙计
And I do the telling on this planet, Kirk, old boy.
你听着就好
You do the listening.
很好，我听着
All right, I'll listen.
你想说什么？
What are you telling?
也没什么，就是告诉你们开始享受这里吧
Merely that you might as well start enjoying yourselves.
这地方真的很不错
It's really a very, very nice place.
估计你们
And you're all going to be here,
下半辈子
quite probably,
都要待在这里了
for the rest of your lives.
哈里·马德，你这个法外之徒，你有大麻烦了
Harry Mudd, you're a liar, and an outlaw, and in deep trouble.
我要求你交还星舰的控制权，放我的星舰走
I want navigational control restored, and my ship released.
抱歉，这不符合法律
Sorry, that'd be against the law.
我的法律
My law.
由马德一世颁布
Decreed by Mudd the First.
全体公民投票通过
Voted in by the resident population.
她们很可爱吧？
Lovely, aren't they?
寇克，你得承认，我的眼光还是不错的
You must admit, Kirk, that I still retain my eye for beauty.
我宣布，我的周围必须有美人环绕
I decreed that I should always be surrounded by it,
我的法令一定会被全票通过
and my decrees always come to pass.
有500位这样的美人侍候我
I've had 500 of them made up to attend me.
她们长得完全一样
All of them identical, beautiful,
美丽，温柔，又听话
compliant, obedient.
500个一模一样的模特儿？我觉得有点多了
Five hundred of the same model? That seems rather redundant.
我很喜欢这些模特，史波克先生
I have a fondness for this particular model, Mr. Spock,
这一点，你一个瓦肯人又怎么会了解呢
which you, unfortunately, are ill-equipped to appreciate.
很好，哈里
All right, Harry.
解释一下你是怎么来到这儿的
Explain. How did you get here?
餐宿矿星那件事后我们把你关进监狱了啊
We left you in custody after that affair on the Rigel mining planet.
这个嘛，我组织了一个技术信息服务处
Yes, well, I organised a technical information service,
给落后星球送去现代工业技术
bringing modern industrial techniques to backward planets,
给银河系中正在奋斗的年轻文明
making available certain valuable patents
带去颇具价值的专利知识
to struggling young civilisations throughout the galaxy.
你付报酬给专利所有者了吗？
Did you pay royalties to the owners of those patents?
这个嘛，寇克
Well, actually, Kirk,
作为自由企业体系的捍卫者
as a defender of the free-enterprise system, I found myself
我发现自己陷入了矛盾
in a rather ambiguous conflict, as a matter of principle.
他没付报酬
He did not pay royalties.
先生，知识应属于所有人
Knowledge, sir, should be free to all.
- 谁抓住你的？ - 岂有此理，怎么能这么问！
- Who caught you? - That is an outrageous assumption!
好吧，谁抓住你的？
Yes. Who caught you?
我把瓦肯燃料合成器的所有知识产权
I sold the Denebians
卖给了德纳比人
all the rights to a Vulcan fuel synthesizer.
德纳比人联系了瓦肯人
And the Denebians contacted the Vulcans.
- 你怎么知道？ - 是我是也会这么做
- How'd you know? - That's what I would have done.
这是典型的警察思维
It's typical police mentality.
一点幽默感都没有，他们还逮捕了我！
They've got no sense of humour. They arrested me!
岂有此理
I find that shocking.
不仅如此，你知道德纳比V星球上诈骗罪的处罚是什么吗？
Worse than that. Do you know what the penalty for fraud is on Deneb V?
有罪一方可以选择：电击死刑，毒气死刑
The guilty party has his choice: Death by electrocution, death by gas,
相位炮死刑，绞刑…
death by phaser, death by hanging...
史波克先生，你说了这么多，关键词就一个：死刑
The key word in your entire peroration, Mr. Spock, was..."death."
真是野蛮人
Barbarians.
- 那我当然得离开啊 - 他越狱了
- Well, of course I left. - He broke jail.
- 我借了交通工具 - 他偷了一艘宇宙飞船
- I borrowed transportation. - He stole a spaceship.
巡逻队对我很不友好
The patrol reacted in a hostile manner.
人家朝他开火了
They fired at him.
他们对私人财产连起码的尊重都没有
They've got no respect for private property.
毁了我的宇宙飞船！
They damaged the bloody spaceship!
反正，我逃出来了，不过我不知道航向
Well, I got away, but I couldn't navigate.
所以就游荡到了地图上没有的地方…
So I wandered out through unmapped space...
在这里我找到了…
...and here I found...
…马德
...Mudd.
你历经艰险把星舰开到这里
You went to substantial risk and effort to bring a starship here.
按理来说，肯定有某种强烈的动机
Logically, you must have a compelling motive.
史波克，你肯定会喜欢这里的，他们说话都跟你一个样
Spock, you're going to love it here. They all talk just the way you do.
继续说啊，哈里
Go on, get on with it, Harry.
没错，继续
Yes, well, right, laddie buck.
然后，我就到了这里
Well, so here I am, in a planet
这个星球拥有20万台勤劳欢快机的器人
with over 200,000 hard-working, happy androids,
他们存在的唯一目的就是为了侍奉我的每一个…
all of whom exist merely to serve my every... whim.
真是天堂啊
It's absolute paradise.
那我就不明白你有什么问题了
Then, I am unable to discern your problem.
他们不肯放我走！
They won't let me go!
他们要研究我
They want to study me.
他们想进一步了解人类
They want to learn more about human beings.
- 他们挑的样本不错啊 - 说话注意点，小子
- They picked a fine representative. - Watch your tongue, lad.
你这是在跟马德一世说话
You're talking about Mudd the First.
不管怎么样吧，我没了主意
Well, anyway, I ran out of ideas.
对他们来说我已经没有多大用处了
I simply ran out of things for them to do.
他们坚持让我再带一些人类过来
And they insisted that I bring them more human beings.
他们需要人类供他们侍奉，研究
They need human beings to serve, to study.
所以我答应给他们带些优质样本
So I had to promise them a prime sample.
星舰舰长
A starship captain.
充满生气，刚正不阿，无所畏惧，充满想象的舰长
Bright, loyal, fearless and imaginative.
随便一名舰长都有这些特质，能被我选上是你幸运
Any captain would have done, I was just lucky enough to get you.
所以你要接替我待在这里
So you are going to take over for me here
然后我就可以离开这荒蛮之地，返回文明社会了
and I get off this rock, and back to civilisation.
我可不这么想，哈里
I think not, Harry.
你误会了，小子，我不是请求你，而是命令你
You misunderstand me, lad. I'm not asking you. I'm telling you.
你别无选择
You've no choice.
- 带他们去住处 - 是，马德大人
- Show them to their quarters. - Yes, my Lord Mudd.
这边请
This way, please.
哈里，这是什么？
Harry, what's this?
先生们，这是一个神龛
That, gentlemen, is a shrine
用以纪念我心爱的斯黛拉
to the memory of my beloved Stella.
- 谁？ - 斯黛拉，我的妻子
- Who? - Stella, my wife.
- 她去世了？ - 不不不，只是被抛弃了
- Dead? - Oh, no, no, no, merely deserted.
每一个伟大的男人背后，都有一个女人在不断督促着他
You see, behind every great man, there is a woman, urging him on.
这就是我的斯黛拉
And so it was with my Stella.
她督促我来到外太空
She urged me on into outer space.
她并非刻意为之
Not that she meant to,
而是用她那
but with her continual,
永不停歇的，令人厌烦的唠叨…
eternal, confounded nagging...
我常常想念她
Well, I think of her constantly,
每想她一次，我就深入太空一些
and every time I do, I go further out into space.
真有意思
That's very interesting.
你离开了你的妻子，却又把她带在身边
You leave your wife, and then bring her along.
我让机器人们复制了一个完美的斯黛拉
I had the androids construct a perfect replica of Stella
这样我就可以盯着她，享受远离她的乐趣
so that I could gaze upon her and rejoice in her absence.
先生们，注意了
Gentlemen, attend.
斯黛拉，亲爱的
Stella, dear.
哈考特！哈考特·芬东·马德，你又打什么坏主意？
Harcourt! Harcourt Fenton Mudd. What have you been up to?
肯定没什么好事
Nothing good, I'm sure.
我告诉你，你这个懒惰的，没用的…
Well, let me tell you, you lazy, good-for-nothing...
闭嘴！
Shut up!
很精彩吧？
Marvellous, isn't it?
我终于能对她指手画脚了
I finally have the last word with her,
对你也是
and with you.
你们会喜欢这里的
You will find this quite comfortable.
你们的住处在大厅那边
Your quarters are down the hall.
- 如果有任何需要… - 我需要我的星舰
- If there is anything you need... - Yes, my ship.
我们无权回答此类问题
We are not programmed to respond in that area.
诺曼，谁创造了你？
Norman, who created you?
我们是创造者设计的
The Makers designed us.
他们来自于仙女座星系
They came from the galaxy of Andromeda.
如此说来，你们的创造者不是类人生物了
Then your Makers weren't humanoids.
他们和人类十分相像
They were, as you say, quite humanoid,
但是与你们的文明不同，在那里，机器人十分普遍
but, unlike your civilisation, robots were common.
我们行使一些必要的服务功能
We performed the necessary service functions and freed our makers
- 使得创造者们的社会秩序更加完美 - 他们怎么了？
- to evolve a perfect social order. - What became of them?
我们的太阳变成了新星
Our home planet's sun became a nova.
只有少数勘探部队幸存下来
Only a few exploratory outposts survived.
这只队伍，我自己…
This unit, myself...
…是派往银河系的勘探部队中的一员
...was part of one such outpost in your galaxy.
- 然后，你们的部分创造者幸存下来了 - 没有，舰长
- Then, some of your Makers survived. - No, captain.
时间流逝，他们也去世了
They died, over the stretch of time.
你们如今侍奉谁？
Whom do you serve now?
我们侍奉哈里·马德
We serve Harry Mudd.
他再次向我们提供了目标
He has given us purpose again.
有目标很重要
It is necessary to have purpose.
我们失去目标很久了
We lacked it for a long time.
我们这里藏书量巨大，可供你消遣
We have a very extensive library section for your amusement.
我们的实验室和工作坊
Our research laboratories and workshops
同样设备齐全
are extremely well-equipped.
- 欢迎你们的使用 - 欢迎你们的来访
- You are free to use them. - You are free to visit them.
好好，我们改日再去
All right, we might later.
现在嘛，你们可以退下了
In the meantime, would you mind leaving us?
- 为什么要我们退下？ - 为什么要我们退下？
- Why should we leave you? - Why should we leave you?
因为我们不喜欢你们
Because we don't like you.
好了…
Now...
有什么想法吗？
Well. Opinions?
我觉得我们这次麻烦大了
I think we're in a lot of trouble.
很有用，契诃夫先生，老骨头呢？
That's a great help, Mr. Chekov. Bones?
我同意契诃夫的看法，我们有大麻烦了
Well, I think Mr. Chekov's right. We are in a lot of trouble.
史波克？如果你也说我们有大麻烦…
Spock? And if you say we're in a lot of trouble...
的确有大麻烦了
We are.
我们必须想办法找到麻烦的核心
And we must direct our attack to the heart of the matter.
很明显，这么多机器人不可能独立运行
Obviously, this many androids cannot operate independently.
肯定有中央控制系统
There must be a central control system
来指挥所有的机器人
which guides the entire android population.
想办法找到它，其他人，观察环境，多多学习
Try and find it. The rest, look around. Learn everything you can.
我去看看能从马德先生那里找到些什么，行动吧
I'll see what else I can find out from Mr. Mudd. Let's go.
相信你很喜欢这里吧，史波克先生
I trust you are enjoying yourself, Mr. Spock.
很有趣
Very interesting.
这个设备非同寻常啊
This is a most unusual device.
这是我们的中央控制集合
It is our central control complex.
我记得这里有超过20万个机器人吧？
Did I understand there are more than 200,000 of you?
二十万七千八百零九个
207,809.
这个交换中心看起来很简单啊
This would seem to be a simple relay centre.
你们全部都是通过这个设备控制的吗？
Are all of you controlled through this device?
我无权回答这类问题
I am not programmed to respond in this area.
可以理解
That's quite understandable.
这是我们的芭芭拉系列
These are our Barbara series.
身体表面覆盖着自我修复塑料
The body is covered with a self-renewing plastic
骨架为铍钛合金
over a skeleton of beryllium-titanium alloy.
- 令人惊叹 - 的确令人惊叹
- Very impressive. - I should say so.
我得承认，我喜欢这个风格
Well, I must say, I like the styling.
当然了，她们都是按照我的个人喜好制造的
They were, of course, made to my personal specifications.
还有梅兹系列，特鲁迪系列也是
As indeed were the Maisie series, the Trudy series,
还有我最喜欢的安娜贝尔系列
and particularly the Annabelle series.
你不相信男性机器人吗，哈里？
Don't you believe in male androids, Harry?
男性？他们有别的用途
Male? I suppose they have their uses.
这样的一具躯体能够维持多久？
How long does a body like that last?
我们的机器人躯体还没有损坏
None of our android bodies has ever worn out.
不过，这种型号的预计使用期限是
However, the estimated duration of this model
50万年
is 500,000 years.
50万年？
Five hundred thousand years?
我们的医用机器人可以将人类大脑
Our medi-robots are able to place a human brain
植入与之结构兼容的机器人体内
within a structurally compatible android body.
从此便拥有不老的生命和永恒的美貌
Immortality and eternal beauty.
舰长，我刚刚和诺曼进行了一场十分有趣的对话
Captain, I've just had a most fascinating meeting with Norman.
我确信，我发现了一个至关重要的矛盾之处
I'm convinced that I've discovered a very important inconsistency.
我很高兴你能喜欢，医生
Well, I'm so glad you enjoyed it, doctor.
吉姆，你一定要看看这里的研究设备
Jim, you should see the research facilities.
他们这里的实验室简直是…
They've got a lab down there that...
我可以一辈子待在这里做研究
Well, I could spend the rest of my life studying it.
我就欣赏你这种一心一意追求知识的人
I do so admire a man who devotes himself to knowledge.
你疯了吗，老骨头，没人要待在这个鬼地方
Don't lose your head, Bones, nobody's staying anywhere.
冥顽不灵啊，寇克
Stubborn, Kirk, stubborn.
我不会觉得无聊的，我保证
Well, I wouldn't be bored, I can tell you that.
放开我！什么样的女人…？
Let go of me! What kind of a woman..?
这是最后一个，大人
This is the last one, lord.
妙极了，妙极了！欢迎来到马德王国，史考特先生
Splendid, splendid! Welcome to Mudd, Mr. Scott.
哈里·马德！哦，你这个卑鄙小人
Harry Mudd! Oh, you bogus rat, you.
这一切都是你干的吧？
You're the cause of all this, are you?
我命令你留守星舰的啊
You were ordered to stay aboard.
没错，舰长，我是在留守
Aye, sir, and I stayed,
后来被那个女巨人扔进了传送光束
until that female gargantua threw me into the transporter beams.
她刚说“最后一个”，什么意思？
What does she mean, "the last one"?
我没有告诉你吗？
Didn't I tell you, Kirk?
我传送了几十名机器人到你的星舰上
I beamed a few dozen androids up to your ship.
在过去的几小时里，他们把你的船员都传送下来了
They've been sending your crew to the surface for the past couple hours.
现在你的船员全都在这里了
They're all down now.
你疯了吗？
Are you out of your mind?
怎么能把所有人都传下来
You can't beam down an entire crew of a spaceship.
星舰上得有人值班
Somebody has to be onboard.
你的星舰上有人啊，一队机器人船员
There is an entire crew aboard. An entire crew of androids.
他们学东西很快的，舰长
They learn very quickly, captain.
现在的情况是，我已经接管了你的整个星舰
The fact is, I've taken over your whole ship.
你无能为力
There's nothing you can do about it.
哈里
Harry.
哈里，你逃不掉的
Harry, you'll never get away with it.
- 谁能拦得住我？ - 星际舰队
- Well, who's to stop me? - Starfleet.
可是现在我有自己的星舰了，跟舰队里其他星舰一样快
But now I have a ship of my own, and it's as fast as any in the fleet.
他们要怎么抓住我？
How will they catch me?
自己想想吧，小伙子
Just think of it, laddie buck.
哈里·马德手下的可爱船员已经占领了你的星舰
Harry Mudd, with his own crew of lovelies, aboard your vessel.
- 自己想想吧 - 我尽量不想
- Think about that. - I'm trying not to.
爱丽丝
Alice.
他的确很可能成功的，舰长
He could successfully accomplish it, captain.
我问过一些机器人，他们完全忠于马德
I've questioned some of the androids, and they are totally loyal to Mudd.
可能我们更需要关心的是，这些机器人
Perhaps of more concern is the fact that this android population
确确实实可以提供一个人类所要求的一切
can literally provide anything a human being could ask for,
而且不限量
in unlimited quantity.
我知道，这也是我担心的，我的船员们在
Yes, I know. That's what worries me. How will my crew react in a world
一个想什么就有什么的世界里…
where they can have absolutely everything they want simply by...
…会变成什么样？
...asking for it?
- 你需要什么吗，大人？ - 你需要什么吗，大人？
- You desire something, lord? - You desire something, lord?
哦，谢谢你们
Oh, yes, thank you.
- 你是爱丽丝118
- You're Alice 118. - 118.
- 你是爱丽丝322
- And you're Alice 322. - 322.
哎，这又有什么关系呢，你们俩都很可爱
Well, it doesn't make much difference, you're both lovely.
- 谢谢夸奖，大人 - 谢谢夸奖，大人
- Thank you, my lord. - Thank you, my lord.
你需要什么吗，大人？
You desire something else, lord?
- 真可惜你们不是真的 - 我们是真实的，大人
- What a shame you're not real. - We are real, my lord.
- 哦，我是说真正的女孩子 - 我们具有人类女性
- Oh, I mean real girls. - We are programmed to function
- 所具有的一切功能，大人 - 真的？
- as human females, lord. - You are?
- 是的，大人 - 是的，大人
- Yes, my lord. - Yes, my lord.
哈里·马德设定了你们？
Harry Mudd programmed you?
- 是的，大人 - 是的，大人
- Yes, my lord. - Yes, my lord.
这个毫无原则，好色成性
That unprincipled, evil-minded, lecherous
无恶不作的哈里·马德设定了你们？
kulak Harry Mudd programmed you?
- 是的，大人 - 是的，大人
- Yes, my lord. - Yes, my lord.
这地方比列宁格勒还美好
This place is even better than Leningrad.
真是了不起啊
Absolutely fantastic.
精细的手工工艺，微视还有纳秒激光技术
Handworked to the finest tolerances. Microvision and a nanopulse laser.
我从来没见过这样的东西
I've never seen the like before.
你可以命令我们为你做任何事
You may command us to make anything for you,
或者亲自动手，享受其中的乐趣
or do the work yourself, for pleasure.
你可以指定任意数量的工匠为你服务
You may have the services of any number of craftsmen,
可以独享计算机设备
exclusive use of the computer facilities.
所有的一切
Anything.
舰长，你一定要看看这个工坊
Captain, you should see this shop.
他们拥有我们连想都想不到的设备
Why, they have facilities we never even thought of.
这就是你的伎俩吗，马德？
Is that the way you're gonna do it, Mudd?
攻击他们的薄弱点？
Hit my people at their weakest point?
我们只想让你们在这里过得开心舒适，舰长
We only wish to make you happy and comfortable, captain.
我们要侍奉你们，就得了解你们
If we are to serve your kind, we must understand you.
我们的王，哈里·马德
Our Lord, Harry Mudd,
是我们的唯一样本
was only one example for us.
现在，从你们身上我们可以学到很多
Now we are learning a great deal from all of you.
如今我们成了笼中鸟，问题是要怎么逃出去
Here we are, birds in a gilded cage. Question is, how do we get out?
我不知道，长官，不过这个笼子的确精美绝伦
I don't know, sir, but it's a very nice gilded cage.
而且这还是个令人愉快的地方，舰长
And it is a very pleasant place, captain.
他们给了你什么，乌乎拉？
What did they offer you, Uhura?
其实也没什么，就是…
Nothing really important, just...
…永生不死
...immortality.
好了，我们要想办法回进取号，你们别忘了
All right. We're getting back to the ship, and don't you forget it.
站直了
Straighten up.
这精致的笼子里
This may be a gilded cage,
可能有你们想要的一切，但终究是个笼子
filled with everything you want, but it's still a cage.
我们不属于这里
We don't belong here.
进取号才是我们的家
We belong on that ship, up there.
你有什么需要的吗，大人？
Do you require something, lord?
没有，有，我的星舰
No. Yes, my ship.
- 我无权… - 无权回答此类问题，我知道我知道
- I am not programmed... - To respond in that area. Yes, I know.
各位还有什么需要的吗，有什么能让你们开心一点的？
Is there anything any of you require, to please you?
爱丽丝…
Alice...
…把星舰还给我们，就能让我们开心
...give us back our ship, to please us.
把星舰还给我们，那才是我们想要的
Return us to our ship, because we desire it.
我们的使命是侍奉
We are programmed to serve.
我们会全心全意维护你们的最大利益，让你们开心
We shall serve you to your best interests to make you happy.
可是我们在这里不开心
But we're unhappy here.
请解释一下“不开心”
Please explain "unhappy."
当人类的所想和夙愿得不到满足时
Unhappiness is the state which occurs in the human
他们就会陷入“不开心”的状态
when wants and desires are not fulfilled.
你们有什么夙愿没有被满足呢？
Which wants and desires of yours are not fulfilled?
我们想要进取号
We want the Enterprise.
进取号不是夙愿
The Enterprise is not a want or a desire.
它是机器设备
It is a mechanical device.
错，她是一位美丽的女士，我们爱她
No, it's a beautiful lady, and we love her.
出现错误，出现错误，所有相关单位，诺曼，请协调
Illogical. Illogical. All units relate. All units. Norman, coordinate.
未找到词条“不开心”，需做相关研究
"Unhappiness" does not relate. We must study this.
- 有趣 - 真是奇妙啊
- Interesting. - Fascinating.
老骨头，你有没有对这些机器人做心理测评
Bones, have you had time to take any psychological readings of the androids?
做过了，但是没什么用，他们很完美
I did, and you can forget it. They're perfect.
不论是心理上还是生理上都完美无瑕
Flawless, mentally and physically.
没有弱点，十分遵守纪律
No weaknesses, perfectly disciplined.
没有恶习，无所畏惧，目标明确
No vices, no fears, no faults. Just a sense of purpose.
相信我，他们比人类还难对付
Believe me, there's nothing tougher to overcome, even among humans.
没错，这就是我们船员所需要的，目标感
Yes, that's what this crew needs, a little sense of purpose.
马德，我有几个问题要问你
Mudd. A few questions I want to ask you.
恐怕我没时间回答了，我的行李都收拾好了
Afraid I won't have time to answer them. My bags are all packed.
机器人会在24小时内带进取号驶离轨道
The androids will take the Enterprise out of orbit in less than 24 hours.
不过见到你真高兴啊，寇克
But it's been a real pleasure having you here, Kirk.
我能为你做点什么吗？
Is there anything I can get for you?
有，我的星舰
Yes. My ship.
还真是固执
You're a stubborn fellow, aren't you?
不过我完全不介意，毕竟我马上就要离开了
But I don't mind, not at all, because I'll be leaving here quickly enough.
然后你就随意吧
And then you can be stubborn at your own leisure.
最后再来一次
One last time.
斯黛拉，亲爱的？
Stella, dear.
哈考特·芬顿·马德，你又去哪里鬼混了？
Harcourt Fenton Mudd, where have you been?
你又打什么鬼主意呢？
What have you been up to?
你又喝酒了？你这个可怜的酒鬼
Have you been drinking again? You miserable sot!
- 你这个没用的… - 闭嘴！
- You good-for-nothing... - Shut up!
爱丽丝2号，我的可人儿
Alice Number 2, my little love.
你能把我的行李传送到进取号吗？
Will you have my bags transported up to the ship?
- 不行，马德大人！ - 什么？！
- No, my Lord Mudd! - What?!
我们不再听命于你了，哈里·马德
We can no longer take your orders, Harry Mudd.
为什么？
Why not?
我们的创造者很有智慧，赋予了我们侍奉他人的使命
Our makers were wise. They programmed us to serve.
没错啊，我刚才说了，把我的行李传送过去
Yes, but that's what I'm saying. Put my bags on the ship.
我看他们对你有二心啊
I think they have something else in mind.
你说的没错，舰长
You are correct, captain.
就算以人类的标准，哈里·马德也充满了缺点
Harry Mudd is flawed, even for a human being.
我们从一开始就认识到这一点
We recognised this from the beginning,
只是利用他的知识来获得更多样本
but used his knowledge to obtain more specimens.
你们人类正在走向灭亡
Your species is self-destructive.
- 你们需要我们的帮助 - 我们宁愿自救
- You need our help. - We prefer to help ourselves.
我们会犯错误，但我们是人
We make mistakes, but we're human.
我想正是这一点才使得我们成为人
And maybe that's the word that best explains us.
我们不会伤害你们
We will not harm you.
但我们会接管星舰
But we will take the starship
你们会继续留在这颗星球
and you will remain on this planet.
听我说，你不能这么做
Now, look here, you can't do that!
听我说，要侍奉我们，必须服从我们
Now, listen, to serve us, you must obey us.
不，马德大人
No, my Lord Mudd.
爱丽丝1号，服从我，把我的行李送到星舰上
Alice Number 1. Obey me. Put my bags on that ship!
我们不会允许任何像你们人类一样贪婪堕落的种族
We cannot allow any race as greedy and corruptible as yours
自由出入银河系
to have free run of the galaxy.
诺曼，我想知道，你打算怎么阻止人类呢？
I'm curious, Norman, just how do you intend to stop them?
我们侍奉他们
We shall serve them.
这类种族会很乐意享受我们的侍奉
Their kind will be eager to accept our service.
很快，他们就会变得完全依赖我们
Soon, they will become completely dependent upon us.
他们的侵略性和占有欲会在我们的掌控之内
Their aggressive and acquisitive instincts will be under our control.
我们要照看他们
We shall take care of them.
完全可行
Eminently practical.
整个银河系，都被你们掌控？
The whole galaxy, controlled by your kind?
没错，舰长
Yes, captain.
我们会侍奉他们，你们会开开心心…
And we shall serve them, and you will be happy...
…服服帖帖
...and controlled.
目前看来，这件事也有其有趣的一面
So far, this thing has had its amusing aspects.
机器人威胁说要接管
But that threat the androids made
银河系中所有人类这可一点都不有趣
about taking over all the humans in the galaxy is not very funny.
的确
Indeed it is not.
他们成功的可能性很大
They may quite possibly be able to accomplish it.
听我的没错，他们会成功的
Take my word for it, they can.
我们得想办法阻止他们，而且要快
Whatever method we use to stop them, we must make haste.
他们只需要给进取号安装一些控制设备
They have only to install some cybernetic devices on the Enterprise
就可以离开轨道了
and they'll be able to leave orbit.
- 你怎么知道这么多 - 我问他们了
- How do you know so much? - I asked them.
没有理由不回答啊，我们又不能阻止他们
Why shouldn't they answer us? They don't think we can stop them.
你真是太聪明了，寇克
You're so smart, Kirk.
你，还有你那尖耳朵的军师
You, and this pointy-eared thinking machine of yours.
你最好有所作为
Well, you'd better do something
因为我跟你一样着急离开这块红石头
because I'm as anxious to get off this ruddy rock as you are.
我明明记得你打算把我们仍在这个红石头上
I seem to remember that you wanted to leave us on this ruddy rock
然后自己离开的！
and leave by yourself!
这个嘛…
Well...
好了，看看我们都要对付些什么人？
All right, what have we got to work with?
舰长，都是机器人
Well, captain, androids and robots,
他们还不具备独立且具有创造性的思考能力
they're just not capable of independent, creative thought.
可是，诺曼所谓的中央控制系统
Yet, the device that Norman claims to be their central control
完全没能力指挥20多万机器人
is totally inadequate to the task of directing more than 200,000 of them.
我同意
I agree.
那你觉得，是什么在指挥他们？
What, in your opinion, does direct them?
爱丽丝系列，特鲁迪系列下都有很多机器人
There are a large number of Alices, of Trudys,
梅兹，安娜内尔系列也是，根据我的调查
Maisies, Annabelles, and according to my research,
还有赫曼系列，奥斯卡系列…
a Herman series, an Oscar series, a whole plethora of series, in fact...
…可是，只有一个诺曼
...but only one Norman.
诺曼
Norman.
我跟其中一个爱丽丝说
When I told one of the Alices
进取号是位可爱的女士，我们爱他的时候
that the Enterprise was a lovely lady and we loved her
她说：诺曼，请协调。为什么是诺曼，除非…
she said, "Norman, coordinate." Why Norman? Unless...
要想这样运作，每一个机器人都是大型头脑的一部分
To function as they do, each android mind must be one component
通过中央控制系统联系在一起
of a mass brain, linked through a central locus.
其名为诺曼
Named Norman.
组成一个庞大的，极度智能的头脑
Forming one gigantic, highly intelligent mind.
那个发光的徽章…
And the glowing badges...
…标志着这个头脑正在运行
...they indicate the mind in operation.
- 听起来符合逻辑 - 没错，符合逻辑，这点很重要
- That would seem logical. - Yes, logical, that's what it is.
我们可以利用这一点来反击
And that in turn gives us a weapon we can use against them.
我们必须用不合常理、不合逻辑的方法来对付诺曼
We must use wild, insane, irrational illogic aimed right at Norman!
舰长，你歌也唱的好，舞也跳得好
Captain, you sing and dance as well as anyone I've ever seen,
不过你究竟在说什么胡话？
but what the devil are you talking about?
我说的是一个成熟可行的计划，也是我们唯一的机会
What would seem to be a sound, and perhaps our only, opportunity.
机会？
Opportunity?
听我说，史波克，你的确是一个优秀的科学官
Now, listen, Spock, you may be a wonderful science officer,
但是你绝不可能把假专利卖给自己的母亲
but believe me, you couldn't sell fake patents to your mother.
我不明白为什么我要让自己的母亲
I fail to understand why I should care to induce my mother
购买伪造的专利
to purchase falsified patents.
- 算了 - 说重点吧
- Forget it. - Let's get to the point.
哈里，你说过自己想帮忙，对吧？
Harry, you said you wanted to help. Do you?
舰长，对于我来说，由机器人统治的
Captain, the kind of a wholesome, antiseptic galaxy
秩序井然且客观冷静的银河系简直就是炼狱啊
that these androids would run would be purgatory for a man like me.
哈里，不要担心
That's fine, Harry.
我们正好可以在这里制造突破口
The androids will be expecting us to make a break for it.
- 然后你从这里下手 - 我能做些什么呢？
- That's where you come in. - What can I do?
没什么大不了的，哈里，就是…
Nothing, Harry, just...
…睡一觉而已
...go to sleep.
什么…？什么意思？
What..? What do you mean?
别啊，等一下，各位
Oh, no, now, wait a minute, gentlemen.
我觉得还是向他们提出
What I had in mind was actually more on the line
一些金玉良言之类的建议比较好
of a few words of sage counsel, as it were, advice.
哈里，你在这儿吃胖了啊
Harry, I do believe you're putting on weight.
有什么需要的吗？
Yes?
有人病了
We have a medical problem.
你们的前任大王，哈里·马德
Your ex-lord, Harry Mudd.
他是人类，你们要照顾他
He is human. You will have to care for him.
我们可以治好他，但是医生需要去进取号上
We are caring for him, but our doctor needs his medical equipment
拿他的医疗设备
aboard the Enterprise.
人类禁止进入进取号
The starship is forbidden to humans.
给你们设定的任务是侍奉
You are programmed to serve.
如果不允许我们去拿医疗设备
If we're not allowed access to our medical equipment,
哈里·马德就会死，就不能行使他的作用了
Harry Mudd will die. He will cease to function.
你们侍奉的任务也就失败了
You will have failed to serve.
我需要分析目前的情况
I am directed to observe the situation.
- 他出故障了 - 他快死了
- He is malfunctioning. - He is dying.
如果你们带他去进取号的医务室，能修复他吗？
If you take him to your Sickbay, will he be repaired?
- 一定的 - 不
- Oh, yes. - No.
他们在撒谎，这是个骗局
They're lying. It's a trick.
麦考伊医生给哈里·马德注射了什么东西，让他看上去像是生病了一样
Dr. McCoy injected something in Harry Mudd to make him look sick.
他们想要回到进取号上然后毁了星舰
It's a trick to get back on board and sabotage the ship.
- 请求被拒绝 - 乌乎拉，你为什么告诉她？
- The request is refused. - Uhura, why did you tell her?
因为我想要机器人躯体
Because I want an android body.
我想要永生
I want immortality.
我会永远活下去，舰长，我会永远年轻美丽
I'll live forever, captain. I'll be young and beautiful.
你帮了我们的忙，我们会履行义务
You have been of assistance. We shall fulfill our obligation.
谢谢你
Thank you.
我们离开之前会完成对你躯体的程序设定
The programming for your body will be completed before we leave.
乌乎拉…
Uhura...
…太漂亮了！
...beautiful!
我自己都不敢相信
I half believed it myself.
机器人们就等着我们试图逃跑
Well, the androids were expecting an attempt.
- 现在他们如愿了 - 接下来呢？
- And now we've made it. - What's next?
接下来，我们带爱丽丝去漫游仙境
Next, we take the Alices on a trip through Wonderland.
- 你需要什么吗？ - 你需要什么吗？
- Do you require something? - Do you require something?
没错，需要你们集中注意力
Yes. Your attention.
- 他们在干什么？ - 他们在庆祝
- What are they doing? - They're celebrating.
庆祝什么？
What are they celebrating?
庆祝自己被囚禁
Their captivity.
- 你们喜欢这音乐吗？ - 音乐？
- Do you enjoy the music? - Music?
音乐？
Music?
谢谢你，先生
Thank you, gentlemen.
谢谢你，美丽的女士
Thank you, lovely lady.
你的舞跳的真是太棒了
You dance divinely.
谢谢你，善良的先生
Thank you, kind sir.
- 她为什么打他？ - 她喜欢他
- Why does she strike him? - She likes him.
契诃夫先生
Mr. Chekov.
这里无法接纳更多的军官了，立正！
The floor is no place for an officer. Attention!
站直站稳
Now stand absolutely still.
是，舰长
Yes, captain.
现在好多了，契诃夫先生
That's much better, Mr. Chekov.
这不合逻辑
It is illogical.
你说的话不合逻辑
Your statement is illogical.
怎么样了？
How does it look?
完全独立思考，完全遗忘了所有东西
Completely inner-directed. Oblivious to everything.
很好，不知道史波克那边怎么样了
Good. I wonder how Spock's doing.
当然了，你们的计算法完全能够对跨维度的
Of course. Your computations would inevitably lead to a total description
抛物曲面作出完整的描述
of the parabolic intersection of dimension with dimension.
史波克先生，你的逻辑思维和分析能力真是无可挑剔
Mr. Spock, you have a remarkably logical and analytical mind.
谢谢你
Thank you.
这个动作有什么特殊意义吗？
Is there some significance to this action?
我爱你
I love you.
不过，我讨厌你
However, I hate you.
但是我和爱丽丝27完全一样啊
But I am identical in every way with Alice 27.
没错，这就是为什么我讨厌你
Yes, of course. That is exactly why I hate you,
因为你们俩一模一样
because you are identical.
妙极了
Fascinating.
好了，目前为止一切顺利，但我们还没有逃出去
All right, it's worked so far, but we're not out yet.
- 怎么样？ - 成功了，舰长
- Well? - Success, captain.
我们已经除掉了树叶和树枝
We've pruned the leaves and branches of the tree.
现在是时候解决树根了
Now it is time to get to work on the root.
如果说诺曼是控制中心，我们的所作所为肯定会影响他
If Norman is the control centre, he'll be in a bind by what we've done.
如果我们能让他超负荷运转
If we can overload him further,
应该就能让所有机器人失灵
we should be able to immobilise all of them.
大家都明确自己的任务了吗？
Does everybody remember what to do?
- 明确 - 明白了吗？
- Affirmative. - Acknowledged?
你们在这里做什么？
What are you doing here?
我要你们投降
I want you to surrender.
这不合逻辑
That is illogical.
我们移动速度比你们快
We can move more quickly than you.
我们无懈可击
We are invulnerable to attack.
- 我们强大的多 - 不，我们更强大
- We are much stronger. - No, we are stronger.
我会向你证明的
And I'll prove it to you.
你们能伤害自己的主人吗？
Can you harm a man that you're programmed to serve?
不能
No.
但是你们已经伤害他了，诺曼小伙子
But you already have, Norman, laddie.
人类不能只靠面包活着，你这个没有灵魂的可怜虫
Human beings do not survive on bread alone, you poor soulless creature,
人类还需要自由的滋养
but on the nourishments of liberty.
没有自由的人，到底算是什么？
For what, indeed, is a man without freedom?
不过是困在永恒之齿轮中的机器而已
Nought but a mechanism trapped in the cogwheels of eternity.
你们给我的只是健康
You offer us only well-being.
食物、水和幸福对我们来说毫无意义
Food and drink and happiness mean nothing to us.
我们必须有工作可做
We must be about our job.
忍受痛苦和折磨，不停劳作直到永远
Suffering in torment and pain, labouring without end.
在重负之下垂死挣扎，痛哭流涕
Dying and crying and lamenting over our burdens.
- 只有这样我们才会幸福 - 只有这样我们才会幸福
- Only this way can we be happy. - Only this way can we be happy.
这自相矛盾啊
That is contradictory.
这不合逻辑啊
It is not logical.
史波克先生
Mr. Spock.
- 解释一下 - 有何不可？
- Explain. - Why not?
逻辑就是一只婉转动听的鸟，在草地上啁啾
Logic is a little tweeting bird, chirping in a meadow.
逻辑是一只美艳的花环，但是恶臭无比
Logic is a wreath of pretty flowers which smell bad.
你确定你们的寄存器没有故障？
Are you sure your circuits are registering correctly?
你的耳朵是绿色的
Your ears are green.
我无法忍受
I cannot go on.
我受够了幸福
I'm tired of happiness.
受够了舒适愉悦的生活，我准备好了！
I'm tired of comfort and pleasure. I'm ready!
杀了我吧！杀了我！
Kill me! Kill me!
永别了，残忍的宇宙
Goodbye, cruel universe.
他死了
He's dead.
你们不可能杀死他了
You cannot have killed him.
你们没有武器
You have no weapons.
史考特！史考特死了
Scotty! Scotty's dead.
他享受的幸福太多，如今他的幸福更进一步，他死了
He had too much happiness. But now he's happier. He's dead.
我们会怀念他
And we'll miss him.
让我们可怜的死去的朋友听到吧
Let us hear it for our poor dead friend.
什么是人，是那崇高的灵魂
What is a man but that lofty spirit,
是那进取的精神
that sense of enterprise,
是对那无法感知，无法实现
that devotion to something that cannot be sensed,
而只能梦想的事物的无比热爱
cannot be realised, but only dreamed?
是最高的现实！
The highest reality!
太精彩了！舰长！
Brilliant! Bravo! Bravo, captain!
- 你喜欢吗？ - 这不合逻辑
- How did you like it? - That is irrational, illogical.
梦并不是真的
Dreams are not real.
我们的逻辑便是不合逻辑，这是我们的长处
Our logic is to be illogical. That is our advantage.
史波克先生，是时候了，爆炸吧
Mr. Spock, it is time. The explosive.
非常好，舰长
Very well, captain.
- 要爆炸了！ - 别慌
- Explosive! - Don't panic.
女人和孩子先走
Women and children first.
史波克先生，这是不是太多了？
Mr. Spock, isn't that too much for our purposes?
我认为这分量刚好，舰长
I believe that is the correct amount, captain.
- 马德先生，你准备好了吗？ - 好了
- Mr. Mudd, are you ready? - Aye, aye.
当心，别掉了
Careful. I would not want you to drop it.
慢一点
Easy.
小心！小心！
Watch it! Watch it!
炸药
Detonator.
导火索
Fuse.
雷管
Primer.
开关
Mashie.
根本没有什么爆炸！
There is no explosive!
没有？看好了！
No? Observe!
快躲开！
Fore!
你还好么？
Are you all right?
但是，根本没有什么爆炸
But there was no explosion.
- 我撒谎了 - 但是…
- I lied. - But...
他撒谎了，哈里告诉你们的所有东西都是谎话
He lied. Everything Harry tells you is a lie.
记住，哈里告诉你们的所有东西都是谎话
Remember that. Everything Harry tells you is a lie.
仔细听好了，诺曼
Now, listen to this carefully, Norman.
我在说谎
I am lying.
你说你在说谎
You say you are lying,
但是如果你所说的都是谎言，那么你说的就是实话
but if everything you say is a lie, then you are telling the truth.
但是你说的不可能是实话，因为你所说的都是谎言
But you cannot tell the truth, because everything you say is a lie.
可是你说谎…你们说的是实话但是又不能…因为…
But you lie... You tell the truth but you cannot, for you lie...
不合逻辑，不合逻辑
Illogical. Illogical.
请解释一下
Please explain.
你是人类，只有人类才能解释自己的行为
You are human. Only humans can explain their behaviour.
请解释一下
Please explain.
我无权回答这一领域的问题
I am not programmed to respond in that area.
- 我认为他们全部丧失机动性了 - 很好
- I believe they are all immobilized. - Good.
寇克，我的老朋友，我开始佩服你了
Kirk, old man, I'm beginning to develop considerable respect for you.
谢谢夸奖，为什么
Why, thank you.
你愿意和我合作么？
Would you consider entering a partnership arrangement with me?
我有一些想法
I've got some ideas.
合作？你和我？
A partnership arrangement? You and me?
- 没错 - 我也有些想法
- Yes. - I've got something else in mind.
走吧
Let's go.
你一定很不开心吧，史波克先生
Well, you must be very unhappy, Mr. Spock.
开心是人类才有的感情，医生，我并不熟悉这种感情
That is a human emotion, doctor, with which I'm totally unfamiliar.
我怎么会不开心呢？
How could I be unhappy?
这里所有机器人的头脑运作方式都和你一样
Well, we found a whole world of minds that work just like yours:
逻辑性强，毫无感情，求真务实
Logical, unemotional, completely pragmatic.
在一场公平竞争中，可怜而不理智的人类战胜了他们
And we poor, irrational humans whipped them in a fair fight.
现在你又回到了我们这些逻辑混乱的人类中间
Now you'll find yourself back among us illogical humans again.
我对现在的状态非常满意，医生
Which I find eminently satisfactory, doctor.
因为再没有谁比一群毫无逻辑的人类
For nowhere am I so desperately needed
更需要我这样一个逻辑清晰的瓦肯人
as among a shipload of illogical humans.
干得漂亮啊，老骨头
Touché, Bones.
我从未听说过如此厚颜无耻之事
I've never heard of anything so revolting.
我们很快就能见分晓…
We'll soon get to the bottom of this...
寇克，我怎么听说我得留下？
Kirk, now, what's all this I hear about my having to stay here?
没错，马德，我们答应机器人你会留在这里
Yes, Mudd, you've been paroled to the android population of this planet.
机器人有他们的使命
The androids are being reprogrammed.
他们的初始目标是将这座星球改造做生产之用
Their original purpose was to adapt this planet for productive use.
他们会继续这项工作
They'll begin that work again.
可是我留下能做什么？寇克，我又不是科学家
But what do I do? Kirk, I'm no scientist.
没错，你是病源体
No, you're an irritant.
你留下来，做机器人研究的
You'll stay here and provide a first-class example
一等负面样本
to the androids of a human failure.
他们可以近距离观察你，好避免未来出现你这样的人
They'll learn by close observation how to avoid ones like you in the future.
要留多久？
How long?
只要你还是病源体，就要留在这里，所以这取决于你
As long as you continue to be an irritant, Harry. It's up to you.
好吧…
Well...
…如此看来
...I suppose that,
全面考虑一下
taking everything into consideration, as it were,
考虑一下各种不同的可能性，我也能应付的来
and noting all the different possibilities, I could manage.
随着时间的推移
And as detention sentences go,
这里也不会变得
this one isn't
太糟糕
too uncomfortable.
就好像重回银河系了一样
And I'm back in the galaxy again.
你说的没错，还有一件事，哈里
Yes, you are. There's one more thing, Harry.
我们设定了一位特殊的机器人
We've programmed a special android attendant
来照顾你生活的方方面面
to take care of your every need.
她会督促你和机器人一起工作，而不是剥削机器人
She'll help you find an incentive to work with the androids, not exploit them.
要我说，你开化了不少啊，舰长
I call that unexpectedly civil of you, captain.
- 没错 - 哈考特！
- Yes. - Harcourt!
哈考特·芬顿·马德，你又准备做什么坏事？
Harcourt Fenton Mudd, what have you been up to?
又喝酒了？你回答我
Have you been drinking again? You answer me!
斯黛拉，闭嘴
Stella, shut up!
- 你这个可怜的放纵的无赖！ - 我命令你闭嘴！
- You miserable, conniving toad! - I order you, shut up!
整天晚上出去鬼混，回来就跟我编故事
Going out all night and giving me those silly stories!
哈考特！
Harcourt!
哈考特·芬顿·马德！
Harcourt Fenton Mudd!
你又吃那么多，还喝酒！
You've been overeating again, and drinking!
寇克！你不能这么对我，太不人道了!
Kirk! You can't do this to me! It's inhuman!
我看这工作很适合我
I see I've got my work cut out for me.
哈考特！
Harcourt!
你见过酒精里的虫子是什么德行吗？
Have you ever seen a worm in alcohol?
- 喝酒比什么都准时！ - 500号？
- You're on a regular schedule! - Number 500?
你又打什么坏主意呢？
What have you been up to?!
寇克！寇克！你不能这样对我啊！
Kirk! Kirk, you can't do this to me!
太不人道了，寇克！
It's inhuman, Kirk!
别了，哈里，祝你玩得开心
Goodbye, Harry. Have fun.
TLF字幕组欢迎你，欢迎有志之士加入
TLF微博http://weibo.com/tlfsubs/
TLF中文字幕站http://tlfsubs.eastgame.org/